In the previous video,
在之前的视频中
you saw how you can use vectorization to compute their predictions
你知道了如何向量化的计算同时对
the lowercase a's for an entire training set all at the same time.
整个训练集预测结果a
In this video, you see how you can use vectorization to also
在这个视频中 你将学会如何向量化
perform the gradient computations for all m training samples.
计算m个训练数据的梯度
Again, all those at the same time.
强调一下 是同时计算
And then at the end of this video,
在本视频的末尾
we'll put it all together and show how you can derive
我们会将之前讲的结合起来 向你展示
a very efficient implementation of logistic regression.
如何得到一个非常高效的logistic回归的实现
So, you may remember that for the gradient computation,
你可能记得讲梯度计算时
what we did was we computed dz1 for the first example,
我列举了几个例子
which could be a1 minus y1 and then dz2 equals
dz1 = a1-y1
a2 minus y2 and so on.
d2=a2-y2 等等列举下去
And so on for all m training examples.
对m个训练数据做同样的运算
So, what we're going to do is define a new variable,
我们现在可以定义一个新的变量
dZ is going to be dz1, dz2, dzm.
d(大写)Z = [dz1,dz2,...dzm]
Again, all the d lowercase z variables stacked horizontally.
所有的dz变量横向排列
So, this would be 1 by m matrix or alternatively a m dimensional row vector.
dZ将会是一个1*m的矩阵 或者说一个m维行向量
Now recall that from the previous slide,
回忆之前的幻灯片
we'd already figured out how to compute capital A which was this: a1 through
我们已经描述了如何计算A,即[a1,...am]
am and we had defined capital Y as y1 through ym.
我们已经定义了大写字母Y=[y1,...ym]
Also you know, stacked horizontally.
像之前一样 y1,...ym横向排列
So, based on these definitions,
基于这些定义
maybe you can see for yourself that dZ can be computed as
你也许会发现我们可以这样计算dZ
just A minus Y because it's going to be equal to a1 - y1.
dz = A-Y 这等同于
So, the first element, a2 - y2,
[a1-y1,a2-y2...]
so in the second element and so on.
以此类推
And, so this first element a1 - y1 is exactly the definition of dz1.
第一个元素a1-y1就是dz1
The second element is exactly the definition of dz2 and so on.
第二个元素就是dz2 ...
So, with just one line of code,
所以仅需要一行代码
you can compute all of this at the same time.
你就可以同时完成这所有的计算
Now, in the previous implementation,
在之前的实现中
we've gotten rid of one for loop already but we still had
我们已经去掉了一个for循环 但是
this second for loop over training examples.
我们仍然有一个遍历训练集的循环
So we initialize dw to zero to a vector of zeroes.
我们使用dw=0将dw初始化为0向量
But then we still have to loop over training examples where we have
但是我们还有一个遍历训练集的循环
dw plus equals x1 times dz1,
对第一个训练样本有dw+=x1*dz1
for the first training example dw plus equals x2 dz2 and so on.
第二个样本dw+=x2*dz2 ...
So we do the M times and then dw divide equals by m and similarly for B, right?
我们重复M次 然后dw/=m B也类似
db was initialized as 0 and db plus equals dz1.
db被初始化为0向量 然后db+=dz1
db plus equals dz2 down to you know
db+=dz2 这样重复到
dz(m) and db divide equals m. So that's what we had in the previous implementation.
dzm 接着db/=m 这就是我们在之前的实现中做的
We'd already got rid of one for loop.
我们已经去掉了一个for循环
So, at least now dw is a vector and we went separately updating dw1,
至少现在dw是个向量了 然后我们分别
dw2 and so on.
更新dz1 dw2等
So, we got rid of that already but we still
我们去掉了一个for循环但是还
had the for loop over the M examples in the training set.
有个for循环遍历训练集
So, let's take these operations and vectorize them.
让我们继续下面的操作把它们向量化
Here's what we can do, for
我们可以这么做
the vectorize implementation of db was doing is basically summing up,
向量化的实现 db只需要对
all of these dzs and then dividing by m. So,
这些dz求和然后除以m
db is basically one over m,
db=1/m
sum from I equals once through m of dzi and
对dz1到dzm求和
well all the dzs are in that row vector and so in Python,
所有的dz组成了一个行向量 所以
what you do is implement you know,
在Python中你仅需要
1 over m times np.
1/m
sum of the Z.
1/m*np.sum(dZ)
So, you just take this variable and call the np.
你只要把这个变量传给np.sum函数
sum function on it and that would give you db.
就可以得到db
How about dw or just write
那么dw呢
out the correct equations who can verify is the right thing to do.
先写出正确的公式 这才能证明我们做的是正确的
Dw turns out to be one over m,
dw=1/m
times the matrix X times dZ transpose.
dw=1/m*X*dZ转置
And, so kind of see why that's the case.
让我们看看为什么是这样
This equal to one over m then the matrix X's,
这等于1/m乘以
x1 through xm stacked up in columns like that and dZ
列向量x1...xm堆积起来
transpose is going to be dz1 down to dzm like so.
dZ转置是dz1...dzm
And so, if you figure out what this matrix times this vector works out to be,
如果你明白这个矩阵乘以这个向量会得到什么
it is turns out to be one over m times x1
这等于1/m
dz1 plus... plus xm dzm.
这等于1/m*[x1*dz1+...+xm*dzm]
And so, this is a n*1 vector and this is what you actually end up with,
这是一个n*1的向量 也就是你最终得到的
with dw because dw was taking these you know,
因为dw中包括了这些
xi dzi and adding them up and so that's what exactly
xi*dzi 然后把他们加起来
this matrix vector multiplication is doing and so again,
就是这个矩阵和向量相乘做的
with one line of code you can compute dw.
只要一行代码你就可以计算出dw
So, the vectorized implementation of the derivative calculations is just this,
向量化计算导数的实现就像下面这样
you use this line to implement db and use
你用这行代码计算db
this line to implement dw and notice that without the for loop over the training set,
这行代码计算dw 注意我们没有在训练集上使用for循环
you can now compute the updates you want to your parameters.
现在你可以计算参数的更新
So now, let's put all together into how you would actually implement logistic regression.
现在 我们回顾之前所学 看看应该如何实现一个logistic回归
So, this is our original,
这是我们之前的
highly inefficient non vectorize implementation.
没有向量化非常低效
So, the first thing we've done in the previous video was get rid of this volume, right?
首先是我们在前一个视频中做的去掉这一堆
So, instead of looping over dw1,
不用循环遍历
dw2 and so on,
dw1 dw2等
we have replaced this with a vector value dw which is dw+= xi,
我们已经用一个向量化的代码dw+=xi替换这些
which is now a vector times dz(i).
xi是一个向量 给他乘以dzi
But now, we will see that we can also get rid of not
现在 我们不仅要取消那些循环
just for loop of those but also get rid of this for loop.
还要取消掉这个for循环
So, here is how you do it.
你可以这么做
So, using what we have from the previous slides,
用前面幻灯片我们得到的
you would say, capitalZ, Z equal to w transpose X + b
Z=wTX + B
and the code you is write capital Z equals np.
你的代码应该是Z=np.dot(w.T,X)+b
w transpose X + b and then A equals sigmoid of capital Z.
然后A = sigmoid(Z)
So, you have now computed all of this and all of this for all the values of I.
你已经对所有i完成了这些和这些计算
Next on the previous slide,
之前的幻灯片
we said you would compute dZ equals A - Y.
我们知道你还应该计算dZ=A-Y
So, now you computed all of this for all the values of i.
就对所有i完成了这个计算
Then, finally dw equals 1/m x
最后 dw=1/m XdZ.T
dZ transpose and db equals 1/m of you know, np.
db=1/m np.sum(dZ)
sum dZ.
So, you've just done front propagation and back propagation,
你完成了前向和后向传播
really computing the predictions and computing the derivatives on
确实实现了对所有训练样本进行预测和求导
all M training examples without using a for loop.
而且没有使用一个for循环
And so the gradient descent update then would be you know w
然后梯度下降更新参数
gets updated as w minus the learning rate times
w=w-α*dw
dw which was just computed above and B is update as B minus the learning rate times db.
b=b-α*db
Sometimes it's pretty close to notice that it is an assignment,
有时候这和赋值很接近
but I guess I haven't been totally consistent with that notation.
不过我应该没有完全使用这个符号
But with this, you have just implemented
有了这些
a single iteration of gradient descent for logistic regression.
我们就通过一次迭代实现一次梯度下降
Now, I know I said that we should get rid of
我们能不使用for循环时
explicit for loops whenever you can but if you want to
就不要使用for循环 但是如果你希望
implement multiple iteration as
多次迭代进行
a gradient descent then you still need a for loop over the number of iterations.
梯度下降 那么你仍然需要for循环
So, if you want to have a thousand deliveration of gradient descent,
如果你要求1000次导数进行梯度下降
you might still need a for loop over the iteration number.
你或许仍旧需要一个for循环
There is an outermost for loop like that then I
这个最外面的for循环
don't think there is any way to get rid of that for loop.
我认为应该没有方式把他去掉
But I do think it's incredibly cool that you can implement
不过我还是觉得一次迭代就可以进行一次梯度下降
at least one iteration of gradient descent without needing to use a full loop.
而不需要任何循环 这很cool
So, that's it you now have a highly vectorize and
你得到了一个高度向量化的
highly efficient implementation of gradient descent for logistic regression.
非常高效的logistic回归的梯度下降算法
There is just one more detail that I want to talk about in the next video,
这里有一些细节我想在下个视频中讨论
which is in our description here I briefly alluded to this technique called broadcasting.
这里我简单提一下 这种技术被称为broadcasting
Broadcasting turns out to be a technique that Python and
Broadcasting也是一种能够使你的
numpy allows you to use to make certain parts of your code also much more efficient.
Python和Numpy部分代码更高效的技术
So, let's see some more details of broadcasting in the next video.
我们在下个视频中学习关于broadcasting的更多细节